#哈喽大家好
Hello everyone
#前段时间跟大家推荐了这个锅
Previously I recommended this wok to you
#现在还有很多朋友粉丝不懂开这个锅
But many friends and fans still don't know how to "Kai guo" (season a new wok)
#这次我们再来详细介绍一下
Now I'm gonna introduce to you in detail again
#开完锅之后我跟大家煎一个蛋
After seasoning it, I'm going to fry an egg
#证明它操作得当的话是不粘锅的
To demonstrate that food will not stick to the wok if you season it properly
#然后跟大家慢慢讲解
I'll explain to you later
#等一才我四伯来烧火
My uncle will light the fire
#我们农村就是这样子
This is how we do it in the countryside
#笋壳
Outer leaves of bamboo shoot
#普通话怎么说
How to say it in mandarin?
#笋壳
"Sun ko" (in Sichuan accent)
#普通话
In mandarin?
#普通话笋壳
In mandarin, "Sun ke"
#这个笋壳还是挺好的
It's good for lighting the fire
#好 拿锅儿放在上面不是干不起了
Ok. It may not burn if you put the wok on the top now
#好 现在我们把这个锅放上去
Ok. Now we put the wok on the top
#烧到它干为止
Heat it until it's completely dry
#好 我去拿点肥肉过来
Ok. I'm gonna bring some fatty pork
#丢点肥肉进去
Put some fat into the wok
#好香哦这个肥肉
The fat smells really good!
#嘿嘿 好香哦
He he. Smells nice
#其实这个很简单的就是用肥肉下去抹一遍
In fact, (seasoning the wok) is very simple. Just grease the wok with fat
#就用这个肥油涂一下这个锅就行了
Spread the oil all over the wok
#其实一般这样子的话锅就已经开好了
Generally the wok is ready to use after treated like this
#只要这个油润一下锅就行了
Just grease the wok with the oil
#还有我们这个锅拿回去干洗啊
In addition, if you directly wash the new wok with water
#你要是不开锅就直接洗
Without the seasoning treatment
#它这个 叫什么
The... what is it?
#那个灰噶
The dirt
#那个灰很难洗得干净
The dirt cannot be completely cleaned up
#必须要用油脂放进去用猪油进去了之后
You must put pork fat into the wok
#那个油带着这个灰一起洗出来
The lard will remove the dirt during this process
#不开锅不拿油来打过 每次炒的菜都是黢黑的
If you don't treat the wok with oil, the dish will always be dirty and dark
#哦噢 四伯爷的经验还是多老道哦
Wow. My uncle is so experienced
#新锅儿都要打过油 不打油不得行
New woks must be seasoned with oil. Otherwise it doesn't work
#因为猪油它是动物的油
Lard is a type of animal fat
#动物的油它的那个吸附力比较强
Animal fat has a better absorbent ability
#它会把那个铁锅铸出来的时候会把里面的杂质吸得很干净
It absorbs nearly all the impurities generated during the casting process
#菜油就不得行
But vegetable oil can't do that
#还有一个就是猪油炒南瓜尖
Another example is that, you need lard to cook cushaw stem
#它要把那个毛毛都吸起来
The lard absorbs all the tiny "hairs"
#如果是菜油的话就不得行
If you cook it with vegetable oil, it doesn't work
#菜油炒出来的要卡喉咙
You'll chock on cushaw stem cooked with vegetable oil
#是不是
Isn't it?
#它打不到毛毛
Vegetable oil can't remove the hairs
#嗯
Exactly
#现在我来煎2个蛋给大家看一下
Now I'm going to fry 2 eggs to show you
#把鸡蛋打进去
Now put the egg into the wok
#嘿 还安逸
Hey. That's nice
#为什么我要用鸡蛋呢
Why am I using an egg?
#因为鸡蛋这个里面比较好弄一点
Because frying an egg is simple
#如果是用肉丝的话
If I use shredded meat...
#因为肉丝下锅不粘它是有技巧的
Well, you'll need some extra tricks to prevent shredded meat from sticking to the wok
#你要是没有掌握这个技巧 普通人下锅一样的会粘
If you don't know the tricks, the meat is also going to stick to the wok
#一般煎蛋下去不要动它
Generally, don't disturb the egg when you just put it into the wok
#你现在越动它就越粘
The more you disturb it now, the more it sticks to the wok
#这边上这一根都已经掉了
This "fiber" formed on the edge has already dropped (from the egg)
#这个鸡蛋煎好了等一下喂我的狗狗
I'll feed my dog later with this egg
#狗儿 想不想吃
Doggy. Do you want it?
#想吃是吧 等一下
Want it huh? Wait a moment
#火力不够 再放上来
The heat is not enough. Let's put it at the center
#鸡蛋已经在爆了
The egg is popping
#这个锅我也没有洗
I didn't wash this wok
#就是直接把它开了放油进去炸点油出来
I just seasoned it, put some fat inside and extracted some lard #请检查这里
#鸡蛋放下去煎
Then I fried the egg
#其实炒菜不粘锅最重要的是锅里面不要有生水
Actually the most important trick for non-sticky cooking is that there should not be cold water in the wok during cooking
#不要有冷水
No cold water
#炒肉丝的话不要有冷水
Especially when you cook shredded meat
#有冷水的话照样会粘
If there is, the meat will stick to the wok
#你看 现在就可以动了对吧
Look. Now you can safely move it
#如果是太阳蛋的话就直接再煎一会就可以直接拿出来了
If you want a sunny side up egg, you can take it out after a while
#我们再把它翻一下
Let's flip it
#大家看到了吗
Did you see that?
#煎鸡蛋是不粘的
Fried egg doesn't stick to the wok
#好 差不多了
Ok. Almost done
#用来喂我们家的狗狗
I'll feed my doggy with it
#等它冷哈多
Wait till it cools down
#冷哈多啊
Cools down?
#它哪里敢吃嘛这个时候
The dog can't eat it right now
#哪儿哦 这个风吹起一会儿就冷了
It doesn't matter. The wind will cool it down very soon
#它烫的不得吃
It doesn't eat hot food
#来这里
Come over
#烫啊小心啊
It's hot. Be careful!
#好了本期视频就到这里了拜拜
Ok that's the end of this video
#大家对这个粘锅有什么不懂的
If you have further questions about wok-sticking problems
#可以在私信里面评论也可以
Please send me a private message or leave a comment
#我都会尽量给大家解答好吧
I'll try my best to answer
#好嘛收了嘛四伯爷
Ok that's it my uncle
#不烧了四伯爷
Put out the fire please